[
    {
        "difficulty": "easy",
        "question": "67) ...........began wonder could particles exhibit the properties of waves",
        "correct": "   louis de Broglie",
        "incorrect": [" Ruther ford. "
        , "Rydberg"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "easy",
        "question": "68-For a box with infinitely hard walls , the potential is maximum at",
        "correct": "L",
        "incorrect": ["2L", "L/2","3L"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "easy",
        "question": "69-The walls of a particle in a box are supposed to be",
        "correct": "infinitely hard and infinitely large",
        "incorrect": ["small but infinitely hard", "infinitely large but soft", 
        "soft and small "]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "easy",
        "question": "70-Because plank's constant is a very small number , the Heisenberg uncertainty principle is important only for particles with ......",
        "correct": "High masses ",
        "incorrect": [
            " moderate masses",
            " High and moderate masses ",
            "very low masses"
        ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "71-Rutherford's model of the atom",
        "correct": "All of Them ",
        "incorrect": [" Does not yield discrete emission lines ",
         " Does not explain the Rydberg formula"," Is not stable relative to collapse of electron into nucleus"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "72-Classical mechanical model of atomic structure Coulomb attraction plays the role of .......",
        "correct": "gravity",
        "incorrect": [" mass ",
         "Conductivity","Capacity"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "73-According to the Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle,Because a wave is a disturbance that travels in space, it has..........position",
        "correct": "no fixed",
        "incorrect": [
            "the same",
         "a and b","fixed"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "medium",
        "question": "74-The electrons can oscillate (& radiate) equally well at.....Frequency ",
        "correct": "any",
        "incorrect": [ 
        "low", 
        "medium",
        "high"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "(75) The concept of matter wave was suggested by_____",
        "correct": "de Broglie",
        "incorrect": ["Heisenberg", "Schrodinger","Laplace"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "(76) The intensity of the diffraction pattern is proportional to ______ of the wave function ",
        "correct": "square",
        "incorrect": ["forth power",
         "cube", 
        " sixth power"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "(77) The function representing matter waves must be _______",
        "correct": " complex ",
        "incorrect": ["real",
         "zero", 
         " infinity"]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(78) The total probability of finding the particle in space must be __________",
        "correct": "unity ",
        "incorrect": ["zero",
         "infinity","double"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(79) The normalized wave function must have ________ norm",
        "correct": "finite",
        "incorrect": ["zero",
         "unity","complex"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(80) The Non-normalized wave function  must have ________ norm",
        "correct": "infinite",
        "incorrect": [
            "zero",
         "finite","complex"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(81) For normalized wave function ψ→0 as r→___ ",
        "correct": "α",
        "incorrect": [
            " 0 ",
         "1","-1"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(82) The square of the magnitude of the wave function is called_________",
        "correct": "  probability densit",
        "incorrect": [
            "  current density",
         "zero density ","volume density"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(83) The operator ∇ is called _______ operator ",
        "correct": " Laplacian",
        "incorrect": [
            "Hamiltonian ",
         "  IPoisson"," vector"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "(84) _________ principle states that the actual path taken by the light ray is one  which minimizes the integral",
        "correct": " Maupertuis ",
        "incorrect": [
            "Heisenberg",
         " Hamilton’s"," Fermat’s"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "85-Quantum mechanics deals with _____ subject?",
        "correct": "Physics",
        "incorrect": [
            "Mechanics",
         "Mechanics","Electronics"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "86-Schrodinger equation is a part of ____ law? ",
        "correct": " Newtons",
        "incorrect": [
            " Charl’s",
         " Ohms"," None of the above"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "87-Classical mechanics defines ____? ",
        "correct": "Break downs",
        "incorrect": [
            " Force",
         "   All the above"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "88-Which of the following scientist discovered matrix based mechanism of Schrodinger equation? ",
        "correct": "Werner Heisenberg",
        "incorrect": [
            " Richard F",
         " Paul Dirac","None of the above"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": 
        "89-Schrodinger wave equation also help in finding out the ____? ",
        "correct": "Quantum number",
        "incorrect": [
            "Prime number",
         "  Even number"," Odd number "
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "90-A periodic wave has _____ equilibrium positions?",
        "correct": " Zero",
        "incorrect": [
            " Maximum",
         " Minimum","Infinite"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "91-____ is the particles to and fro motion about a mean position? ",
        "correct": "   Oscillatory motion",
        "incorrect": [
            " Damping",
         " Overdamping",
         " Clipping"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "92-Kinetic energy in Hamiltonian operator (H=T+V) is represented as___?",
        "correct": " T",
        "incorrect": [
            " V ",
         "H",
         "S"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "93-Which of the following are the disadvantages of Schrodinger wave equation? ",
        "correct": "  Complicate in understanding physical model of electrons as waves",
        "incorrect": [
            " Aperiodic signal",
         "Newtons third law",
         "All the above"
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "94). A stationary type of state is a ____ state?",
        "correct": " Quantum",
        "incorrect": [
            "Exponential",
            " Linear ",
            "All the above "
        
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "95-Force is expressed in terms of ___?",
        "correct": " Newtons",
        "incorrect": [
            " Joules",
            " Seconds",
            "Meters"
        
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "96-A periodic wave has _____ restoring force? ",
        "correct": "Zero",
        "incorrect": [
            "Maximum",
            "Minimum",
            "Infinite"
        
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "97-A Schrodinger equation governs ____ form of quantum mechanics? ",
        "correct": "  Wave",
        "incorrect": [
            "Air",
            "Noise","All the above "
        
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": "98-A periodic wave is _____ form?",
        "correct": " Sinusoidal",
        "incorrect": [
            " Square",
            " Rectangle ",
            "  All the above"
        
         ]
    },
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": " 99-Potential energy of a Schrodinger equation is _____?",
        "correct": "Additive",
        "incorrect": [
            " Subtractive",
            " Multiplex ",
            " All the above"
        
         ]
    }
   ,
    {
        "difficulty": "hard",
        "question": " 100-Which of the following scientist discovered matrix based mechanism of Schrodinger equation?",
        "correct": " Werner Heisenberg",
        "incorrect": [
            "  Richard F",
            " Paul Dirac",
            " None of the above "
        
         ]
    }
   
]
